<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Piyush Mishra</title>
    <description>Hi, I am Piyush Mishra. I am a QA Engineer and have interest in  computer programming. Welcome to my site.
</description>
    <link>http://piymis.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://piymis.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>2016-04-03 22:00:13 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>2016-04-03 22:00:13 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Markdown basics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Well this is my first post after having created the blog for more than six months. Excuse me for my bad English if you encounter any and do point out the errors if you have time for that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming back to the topic of this post, well I thought it would be better to start with something that I am learning myself and is helpful for even writing this post for my blog.
## Markdown &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well Markdown is simply a writing standard for web and other media which emphasizes simple and easy rules to write in plaintext. Each markdown document consists of a document name and its extension which is &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;.md&lt;/code&gt;. Here &lt;filename&gt; can be any valid filename for your document.&lt;/filename&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Markdown documents are like simple plaintext documents except they are more advanced than them and you can present your plaintext with more options to illustrate visually. There are some simple rules to enhance the presentation of your markdown document. I have listed them below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To make characters bold, you can group the characters in **&lt;chars&gt;\*\* so the result will be like **this**. &lt;/chars&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>2016-04-03 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://piymis.github.io/linux/editors/2016/04/03/markdown-basics.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://piymis.github.io/linux/editors/2016/04/03/markdown-basics.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>linux</category>
        
        <category>editors</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
